# **ADILSON PACHECO**

T: +244-941-161-110 | adilson.pacheco93@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/dodatascience | github.com/Geobuddy

### **PROFILE**

Master graduate specialised in Spatial Data Science. Independent user of Database Management Systems (DBMS), and other analytical tools for data monitoring and management. Ability to use scripting languages such as Python and R to perform analytical tasks for obtaining and manipulating data. Proactive and hardworking individual, able to communicate fluently in three languages. Great attention to detail, ability to meet deadlines and prioritise, in addition to being very punctual and reliable.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **UCL SPACETIME LAB - Unpaid**

London, UK

Software Developer Intern

May 2019 - Sept 2019

- Developed an open-source dashboard for spatial data visualisation and analysis, reducing significant spending costs on proprietary software subscription.
- Wrote technical and non-technical documentation for reference and generate reports.

EURO GARAGES Ascot, UK

Retail Advisor

Aug. 2017 - Fev. 2018

- Responsible for sales, stock management and assortment.
- Implement retail best practices and make customer shopping experience memorable.
- Responsible for management on several occasions in the absence of the manager.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **UNIVERSITY COLLEGE LONDON (UCL)**

London, UK

Master of Science in Geospatial Sciences, GPA: 3.70/4.00

Sept. 2018 - Sept. 2019

- Spatial Databases and Data Management: SQL, PostgreSQL and Post GIS
- Web and Mobile GIS Apps and Programming: JavaScript and HTML
- Spatial-Temporal Data Analysis and Data Mining: R. Python
- Spatial Analysis and Geocomputation: R and Python
- Geospatial Programming: Python
- Dissertation: Development of Open-source Dashboard for Crime Visualisation and Analysis

#### **ROYAL HOLLOWAY UNIVERSITY**

Surrey, UK

Bachelor of Science in Geology, GPA: 3.80/4.00

Sept. 2015 - Jun. 2018

- Computational Earth Science: Python
- GIS And Remote Sensing: ArcGIS

### **CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING**

#### **COURSERA**

Data Warehousing for Business Intelligence Specialisation

Sept. 2020 – Present

#### **COURSERA**

IBM Data Science Specialisation

Oct. 2019 – May 2020

### **SAP**

Introduction to Statistics for Data Science

Oct. 2019 - Nov. 2019

## **SKILLS**

**Programming**: Proficient in Python (Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn, Django), R, SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL, PostGIS), ArcGIS, QGIS, Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Word); Intermediate in JavaScript, HTML, RestAPI, Unix.

Languages: Native language Portuguese; Fluent in English and French.

Memberships: Association of Geographic Information (UK), Royal Institute of Chartered Surveyors (UK)

Driving License: B